let's solve a challenging derivative
problem using logarithmic
differentiation our goal is to find the
derivative of y = x raed to the natural
log of x this is a complex function
where X appears both in the base and in
the exponent let's start by letting y
equal x to the lnx power the key to
solving this type of problem is to take
the natural logarithm of both sides
using the logarithm property that says
Ln of X raised to a power equals that
power * lnx we can simplify this to Ln x
* Ln X or Ln x^2 now comes the key step
we're going to differentiate both sides
with respect to X on the left side we
get 1/ y *
dydx and on the right side we get 2 Ln x
* the derivative of Ln X which is 1 /x
Let's solve for dydx by multiplying both
sides by y then we can substitute back y
= x to the Ln X power finally we can
simplify this to get our answer let's
highlight the key techniques we used to
solve this problem first we used
logarithmic differentiation by taking
the natural log of both sides second we
used logarithm properties to simplify
the expression and finally we use the
chain Rule and product rule for
differentiation therefore the derivative
of x to the Ln X power is 2 * x^ of Ln X
- 1 * lnx this is a great example of how
logarithmic differentiation can help us
solve complex derivative problems